<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Yue Hu</title>
    <link>https://hu-yue.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Yue Hu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Yue Hu &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://hu-yue.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hu-yue.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hu-yue.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a tenure track assistant professor in the Department of Mechanical &amp;amp; Mechatronics Engineering at University of Waterloo since 2021.
Before UW, I had lived and worked in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my bachelor degree in Electronics Engineering in 2011 from University of Genova, in Italy.
Then in 2013 I obtained my masters&#39; degree in Advanced Robotics (EMARO - European Master in Advanced Robotics) from both University of Genova and Ecole Centrale de Nantes (France).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2013 to 2018 I was in Heidelberg, Germany, working mainly on the humanoid robot iCub, and the analysis of human walking. I carried out my PhD in robotics (Computer Science) with the Optimization in Robotics and Biomechanics (ORB) group, at Heidelberg University, under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Katja Mombaur and Dr. Francesco Nori (Italian Institute of Technology). I obtained my degree with Summa cum laude in April 2017. I was then postdoc at ORB until February 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I was postdoc at the Dynamic Interaction Control Research Line lead by Dr. Daniele Pucci, at the Italian Institute of Technology in Genova, Italy, where I worked mainly on whole-body control and teleoperation of the iCub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2018 and 2021 I was in Japan, developing my own research direction of social-physical human-robot interaction, starting from (but not limited to) collaborative manipulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2018 to 2020 I was a JSPS (Japan Society for the Promotion of Sciences) postdoctoral fellow under the supervision of Dr. Eiichi Yoshida, at the CNRS-AIST JRL (Joint Robotics Laboratory), at the National Institute of Advanced Industrial Sciences and Technology (AIST), in Tsukuba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between 2020 and 2021, I was an assistant professor at the GVLab lead by Dr. Gentiane Venture, in the Department of Mechanical Systems Engineering at Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
